come back to me anna finish all the way
you're not finishing good today
better
backhand
oh again
i know we got a little bit of a problem
on the back end you're trying to do open
stance maybe not on purpose you're too
open on the back end
and then you're kind of falling
backwards you go like you go here and
then you're going like this
backwards evacuated yeah you have to set
it up to bring the dominant leg across
the body on the two-handed backhand
across
that way
watch ball comes
this
yay there we go there you go now you're
going to be turned more you're going to
rotate into the contact less likely to
fall back you do a few across
you're too close and you're jamming
yourself every single time leave more
distance between you and the ball
that was better more do you know what i
mean by distance yes yeah lateral
spacing here we go come on
back to the middle do you see this come
on anna you got this you got it don't
worry about it
best one so far you're going to shade
take a quick break
you need lateral spacing
and you need to make a big turn
okay but then i feel like i'm getting
stuck a little bit after this
right now
and i'm kind of stuck no you're not no
no you're gonna bring that back foot
around when you're done
and then you're not gonna be stuck so
like that
hit
that's fine you're gonna bring the back
leg around
and then you're gonna come back to the
middle of the court
here i'll show you
you're gonna come in here lateral set up
like this but now make sure that you
don't over run the ball you get too
close you know start framing again here
you're going to hit the ball now when
the racket goes towards the end of the
swing now you can come around with this
leg
and then go back to the middle try it
again ready position and come
still frame
you're too close need more distance to
the ball come on
better
again
better anna
come on
and i yeah i see you're hopping around
too much today why are you doing that
i read the comments that i'm very
stationary so okay are you are you are
you learning tennis from
are you learning tennis from commenters
or you learn tennis from me
because you're today you're hopping
around you're bouncing around yeah i'm
teaching your footwork
right yeah but i'm not teaching you
footwork yet
i know we're teaching strokes first yes
step by step if we throw everything at
you at once you're gonna get confused
and you're gonna quit tennis you're
gonna hate it so moving in place while
you're waiting for the ball no problem
at all but what's happening now is that
you're you're moving too much and you're
over running the ball you're hopping
into the ball and you're not letting the
stroke you're not preparing the stroke
properly and you're not finishing the
stroke properly so just don't overdo it
yes i do want you to move your feet but
don't be hopping around senselessly i
want to teach you the footwork the
intuitive way
so you have to be patient yeah when you
are getting a ball this easy it's
unnecessary to do too many steps
it's a very predictable ball there's
going to be circumstances where you're
going to make more steps and less steps
in this type of drill it's a pure
technical drill we're trying to work on
your two-handed backhand the ball is
very predictable you don't have to move
that much
that makes sense because we right now
we're just trying to fix your backhand
because when we were rallying you were
missing a ton of them yeah i don't know
so some days are like that so when
that's the case
pure technique we either do it
stationary or we do it very lightly to
towards the side with just a few steps
and then the next progression would be
doing it in a real rally situation and
then of course on the run but that's way
ahead let's go step by step okay
okay that feels a little better right
okay it's still late but so the distance
would be somewhere around here
like this that's where you got to hit it
so this is as much space as you need
aiming this way
super straight don't i'm not talking
about that i'm talking about the
distance from your body to the ball
right here this is about as far away
from the ball that you need to be when
you're setting up
okay
much better anna
okay do it again
much better what do you think is this
work
you have to kind of
see visually the ball to be
very close to your belly button
right oh you talk about forward backward
spacing that's different
that's going to be a little bit more
complex i don't want to worry about that
it's not wrong right now the way you're
hitting it but in actuality the contact
is going to be for your back and the
style that you have
it's going to be closer to the body
because you have both arms bent when you
make contact so the style will be closer
to your body there's a feel that's what
you're feeling right now and that's not
wrong at all
there's two different type of spacings
in tennis there's the forward backwards
spacing this way
okay how far away from the ball you are
or how far
the ball is away from you this way and
then there's the lateral spacing to the
sides
that's what you have trouble with
the reason why you have trouble with it
today and never before is because you
were reading comments and trying to
learn from the comment section
right everybody was giving you a
footwork advice so you were overrunning
the ball moving too much
okay
all right here we go come on come on
much better
good
and accelerate properly come on
good and again
fantastic
that one has sounded good didn't it
you're too far away
but that was a bad bounce yeah here we
go
that was better but then rip it come on
don't be careful go for it let it go
anna is absolutely perfect i love that
one okay now next progression let's try
to rally a little bit i still have a few
balls left we try to rally a little bit
come on anna yeah
the back end is fixed we repaired it are
you happy
yeah okay good i hope so i don't know
sometimes what's wrong
sometimes it's few steps back in any
learnings no
um a little bit
maybe the brain is i don't think so
i don't think so i don't think so i
think it's pos it's the tennis is a game
where you will have bad days for sure
that's what i'm saying yeah i don't
believe in the idea that you're going to
go backwards first before you go
forwards
not in tennis technique the tennis
technique has to immediately show you a
better feeling and an improvement
and doesn't mean it's a bad day
how do you describe it's complex because
on a bad day
it could be your timing that's off
it could be your footwork
it could be many different things maybe
you were
emotionally different the way you're
playing maybe you're trying to hit too
hard maybe you're too scared and too
careful it could go wrong that way so
all these different things can happen to
you and also don't forget there could be
the ball coming at you from the other
side they're coming at you differently
and when it's coming at you differently
from what you're used to you might have
a bad day
yeah because nobody talks about it
really and um
i'm resilient i can go through this yeah
i know i will be better because i'm
trying hard and i practice yeah
but a lot of people give up because they
think one day is bad another day is bad
and everybody talks about it a lot it's
an epidemic people are quitting tennis
and record numbers they're going over to
pickleball
you know pickleball right yep so i've
tried it once i was like ah when i'm 120
yeah i will probably do that i'll join
you when i'm 100 let's do that i'm not
going to
i'm not going to be revealing if i tell
you my age then i would reveal your age
i'm going to do that so anyway you know
what
uh this is exactly why people are going
to pickleball because tennis is so hard
um it takes so much work it takes so
much patience the improvement is so
gradual so slow that people get
frustrated
and they end up quitting where
pickleball is a lot easier to pick up
and they see faster results this is why
again
in the comment section now i can't tell
you what to do you do whatever you want
but don't take comments to heart where
people say you're not getting better you
have shown tremendous amount of
improvements in one year it's been
exactly one year since you started if
you compare a video of you playing a
year ago to now this is night and day
this is absolutely insane how much
you've improved
four five
six
seven
eight
no now to you it doesn't seem like that
because all you remember is the last
month or the last two weeks and it feels
like you didn't get better at all maybe
you think today you got worse but
because in tennis the improvement is so
gradual you feel like you're not
improving at all the only way you can
see improvement if you look at it from a
year before or two years before that's
the crazy thing about tennis that's why
goal setting in tennis has to be long
term step by step here we go
still too close come on space it
good work again
good attack it get up
come on come on
love that get now get this one back come
on
good try and a good try now here's one
thing you can start doing i'll show you
here go in the bass line get a ready
position and start bouncing around like
this watch
let me see you i'll go down with the
upper body a little bit look at this
see this watch
do that let me see
do that in between the shots
a little bit yeah a little bit forward
there you go do that between the shots
that's excellent and then when the ball
goes you go because here
i'm giving you high intensity
artificially because i'm not giving your
balls in the same place i'm moving you
all over the place all right but if we
happen to hit more of a stationary
tennis this is where you have to avoid
what a lot of players do is you get
stuck standing like this yeah remind
yourself to move i have another question
right so the guy in one comment said
that i have to say it was a russian
comment by the way was that it
have you not learned from your coach to
sit
lower under the ball why are you
standing straight
on straight legs and sticking out your
butt
so what do you say about that
you're driving me crazy with the
comments i don't know what are you doing
stand on the street
and keep my butt out and i was supposed
to be like sitting under the ball here's
the the logic there to apply to
everything that you read
if it was good to hit a forehand by
sitting in a chair
then i would have told i would have
taught you this yeah did i ever show you
to her forehand like this that hit sit
in a chair
no i told you remember when the ball is
low you stay low
yeah all right now when you're in this
position that i just showed you it's a
slight bend it's like a slight bending
position like this see naturally this is
good enough yes now what else did i tell
you remember what i told you a while
back i take a wide base when you set up
naturally when you do a wide base you
know what happens
you get a natural knee bend intuitive
knee bend so if i do a wide base
naturally i'm going to be bent
you understand
same on the back and we just did 10
minutes ago doing the lateral step if
you do a wide base naturally there's
going to be some bend in there
if you're a little bit too far like this
that is maybe too much slightly down is
enough i've noticed in my match i'm a
little bit this way if you're waiting on
a well first of all if you're waiting
there's no problem waiting like that you
look at the pros when they wait on the
return of serve there are some that are
like this oh really
sure
no well i've seen it i'm telling you
about it yeah now in between the shots
maybe that's a little bit too low it
might be a position that's more
difficult to get out of
do a sprinter's position sprinter stance
like sprinters are like this slightly
down with the upper body because that's
going to give you the best possible
chance to react quickly to the incoming
ball okay okay here we go come on
okay
much better anna get up
anna excellent job very nice let's go
the other way a little bit okay
good anna
much better
spacing
no you're too close
attack at a come on
that's not a volley though it's a
regular forehand yeah remember our last
lesson was the short forehand
you go here to the side remember that
you get a short half forehead you run
through the racket to the side you have
been handled as a as a forehand forehand
but the racket remember half court
forehand racket goes to the side that's
the first thing you do then you run what
if i ran faster could i
you
you could have but it was it's
definitely difficult to do volleys from
that far back
you're better off vowing when you're
closer
okay
so that would be an unnecessary risk
i don't know how to identify which i
understand it's
not yet it's hard i know
here we go
beautiful forehand
ana it's looking better
ana is looking better
get up there come
and volley come on valiant
get closer valley
lolly valley valley valley
good
uh
it's okay anna don't worry
maybe the best
you like it right
i think the best backhand you hit today
very good job nice hannah very good ana
how are you feeling now about your
backhand you feel a little better i feel
that you fixed my mind okay good and i
feel
like it's important that the coach
actually fixes your mind because your
mind can take you places oh yeah and
you're gonna suck and then you're gonna
be discouraged and you're gonna just
quit short-term memory it's one thing
that additional thing i can tell you is
that when you make mistakes
i i don't mind you getting angry
sometimes you can't control that part
but i want you to forget about them as
quickly as possible if you're playing a
match same thing if you lose a match
forget about it as quickly as possible
don't dwell
on on mistakes uh don't over analyze
your mistakes don't over dramatize your
own mistakes shake it off go into the
next ball
instructions are very simple that we're
doing
and i think the back end today improved
quite a bit i am blessed i have a
forgiving coach nice work
nice work hannah nice work